=Remnants of Gold=
(Adapted from Gu Long's
"Flying Eagle over the Great Land")
(The main characters
in this drama are fictional)
=Episode 5=
What are you doing up there?
Luyao told me to keep watch.
Have we met somewhere before?
You look really familiar to me.
Where are you guys from?
Liangzhou.
From Deputy Military
Commissioner Yu's residence.
My friend,
on this journey west,
I can protect you.
Think about it. You're all alone,
carrying 100 taels of gold.
Isn't that a lot?
It is.
When we were drinking just now,
I heard you say
that it doesn't matter
if you don't get the gold, right?
Even if I don't want it,
it's none of your business.
Get down here.
Who's that?
Heroine.
Put this on.
From Luyao?
From me.
I told you to put it on.
Fang is a spy, too.
I saw the spear
in Yu Hou's room before.
Though it was wrapped in a cover
and hidden in a corner.
Fang is a good person.
He's pure and kind-hearted.
He doesn't realize
what he's being made to do,
nor does he know what will happen next.
Why would they send someone like him?
Deputy Yu sent him?
Most likely.
Is the Deputy Military Commissioner
our enemy, too?
I have many dark thoughts in my heart,
but I've never dared to act on them.
What if the General
harbors dark thoughts as well?
My father said
the Commander-in-Chief
is the deity of the Northwest.
A deity has no dark thoughts.
We'll know as we keep going.
Treat Fang just like before.
Don't blow his cover.
Luyao,
are you asleep?
No.
When we were at the Escort Agency,
I thought
I saw brother-in-law.
Just for a split second.
In the candlelight,
in the blink of an eye,
he was gone.
Brother-in-law can't even walk.
How could he possibly
come to the Northwest?
I'm really scared.
Don't be scared.
I must have mistaken him
for someone else, right?
Never call him
"brother-in-law" ever again.
If we die this time,
that will be the end of it all.
If we survive,
we won't go back to Northern Shu either.
What an agonizing wait.
How long have you been
sitting under the General's armor?
I was about to go to sleep.
Go back where to sleep?
That's the General's bedroom.
I am a General, too.
A guerrilla commander.
Every day,
I brew a pot of medicine
for the General.
I will repeat that.
Every day,
I brew a pot of medicine
for the General.
Everyone in Gansu watches
as I finish
brewing the medicine,
bring it inside,
and walk all the way
to this very spot.
Then, I pour out all the medicine
right here
and walk back out holding
the empty golden medicine pot.
Yu Hou,
you can smell it.
This entire patch of sand
reeks of medicine.
Why do I pour out
the medicine right here?
Yu Hou,
do you understand now?
Don't touch it with your hands.
My poison
dissolves bones.
It was poured
over the General,
jar after jar.
The General,
piece
by piece,
just vanished.
Now, no one knows
that the General is buried here.
Two months ago,
a few personal attendants knew.
I killed them all.
Luyao, you won't die.
If we don't go back to Sichuan,
we'll just go somewhere further.
The further, the better.
Where should we go?
Why aren't you crying out?
We've fought until now,
but why didn't you shout?
If you shout a bit louder,
the warriors out
on the drill grounds could hear you.
If I tighten my grip just a little,
your life
will be gone.
But you can't be
buried here like the General.
Not because it's too crowded here,
but because
the General left
a suit of armor outside.
And you?
You have nothing.
So I'll give you another chance.
Whatever I say,
you repeat it.
Think it through
as you speak.
Speak carefully.
Don't make a mistake.
A man of his word, true to his actions.
Yu Hou,
you have always been
someone who delivers on his promises.
That's why the General was fond of you.
The General
is dead.
Say it!
The General
is dead.
But as long as
the General's armor remains,
the deadly presence
of Gansu remains.
As long as the General's armor remains,
the deadly presence
of Gansu remains.
If
the imperial court
sends a new General,
and the armor
is no longer there,
we'll be gone, too.
Once the armor is no longer there,
After following the General
through life and death for 20 years,
we must make plans for ourselves.
We must make plans
for ourselves.
Have you ever considered
dying of old age in
this remote desert borderland?
You like
Jiangnan silk
and frontier incense.
Did you think I didn't know?
Those are far too expensive.
They aren't things we ought to possess!
The armor won't stand for long.
Soon enough,
someone will strip it down.
Say it.
The armor won't stand for long.
Someone will strip it down.
We must act quickly.
Only gold lasts forever.
Three hundred thousand taels of gold.
You and I split it half and half.
I'll go to the Western Regions,
and you
can go to Jiangnan.
One hundred fifty thousand taels of gold
is enough to spend the rest of our lives
wearing the finest silk
and seeing the finest dancers.
Half and half.
What about Tie Futu?
What about him?
Let martial artists handle
martial arts world matters first.
Tie Futu thinks he has many experts
and can run rampant
across the Northwest.
In Gansu, among the twelve guards
and four battalions,
sending out just
a single guard of heavy cavalry
could wipe him off.
Open the door.
Close the door.
(Heisong Post)
Are you asleep,
my friend?
Why don't you sleep
in the room upstairs?
I can't part with my salt.
It's the finest salt from the Gesa Sea.
Zhang Luyao.
I'm not feeling well.
My Chong and Yang Heel Meridians
are a bit blocked.
Before we left Liangzhou,
you said you'd give me
an antidote every five days.
Is that not enough?
Give me a dose first.
Power is surging through
my Baihui and Fengchi points.
Is it because of
the fighting and drinking?
Drinking does make one
lose their mind and senses.
I borrowed troops as you asked.
Don't forget about
giving me the antidote.
Don't speak.
When I came up just now,
I felt a chill in my joints.
I even started hallucinating.
What
are you doing here?
Watching over my two bags of salt.
Where did you come from,
and where are you headed?
From Xining Guard.
Sell salt, buy liquor,
and go back to the Wusu Sea.
Hide if you don't want to die.
Get out.
What about my salt?
We're all in this together,
hunting the criminal.
Don't use me and then throw me away.
Don't speak.
Alright, I'll head down.
Seriously,
I feel dizzy and weak.
Wake up the guards.
The person you want to arrest is here.
You go down first.
I'll go from the window
and block both sides.
What are you doing?
Dummy, sleeping?
If you're going to sleep, go inside.
Who's there?
Why are you staring at me like that?
Fine.
If you won't leave,
then stay right here.
Go.
Wake the men up first.
Yes, sir.
Who are you?
Where is the Zhang lady?
In the room up there.
Wait, I'm talking to you. Who are you?
My name is Tie Futu.
Step aside, you two.
I opened
the window for you.
Come to the window to talk!
Take a breath.
Is power surging through
your Fengchi and Baihui points?
What monster are you?
Zhang Luyao,
come over to the window and talk.
Fall.
Down you go.
Arrest the criminals.
Arrest the criminals, Coroner!
Move!
Yes, sir!
Don't move.
Don't get in the way
of Futu's work.
Pingping,
bring a chair over to the window.
Miss Zhang,
I know you're skilled with poison,
so I poisoned you as well.
Luyao,
I don't have any strength left.
For 30 taels of gold,
I hired the Ghost Tycoon
and his wife all the way from Fengdu.
In this world,
the Tang Clan isn't
the only one who can use poison.
His poison
is far more potent than the Tang Clan's.
If you still don't move,
I'm coming up.
Miss Zhang,
I poisoned you
just so we could have a proper talk.
I won't harm you.
It wasn't easy getting you back here.
Back off!
Kill him.
He's interrupting me.
Why aren't the Liangzhou guards moving?
Nobody move.
If you hurt the guy,
there's nothing left
for us to talk about.
Isn't this lad
just someone you hired?
His life or death shouldn't matter.
Do you want to talk or not?
Don't move.
Speak.
I came here to talk
to you in the first place.
Fang,
come down below the window.
Miss Zhang,
people in this world come for profit
and leave for profit.
Life and death pass in a rush,
so don't beat around the bush.
Give it to me straight.
Were you the one who placed
the escort order with my family?
Yes.
You lured the guardians of the gold
to wipe out my family
just to force me back to help you
identify the poison and track them down?
That wasn't it.
The Fengdu Ghost Couple
are right behind me.
Why bother making excuses?
I'm not making excuses.
I want to make things
even clearer for you.
The one who placed
the escort order with the Zhangs
was me.
The one who used the poison
was also me.
The Zhang Escort Agency is so small.
What if the guardians of the gold
didn't care for it?
It just so happened I had
some poison from the feed on hand,
so I used it along the way
to welcome your return to Liangzhou.
The one placing the escort order
and the one poisoning
were both you?
That's right.
Both are me.
In broad daylight,
under a clear...
under a clear sky,
you dare to openly talk about
murder and robbery like this.
Coroner,
do you still want to go back
to Liangzhou or not?
The official and the outlaw
are in cahoots.
Shut him up.
What are you doing?
Slapping my face?
I am an officer of
the Embroidered Uniform Guard!
We are mortal enemies now, huh?
What are you looking at?
My friend,
I'm just taking a look
and listening in.
Placing the order and
poisoning them were both you,
and it had nothing to do
with the guardians of the gold.
Why tell me all this?
I was planning to head west anyway
to look for the guardians of the gold.
Lamp Shade is dead,
and having you trailing
behind me is too much trouble.
Your father and brothers,
all twenty-seven dead,
can't be brought back to life.
The people you hired
are no match for me.
The troops you borrowed
won't stand in my way.
Forget about
revenge.
Why not get rich together instead?
We head west together
and track down
the guardians of the gold.
Tell me.
Out of 300,000 taels of gold,
I'll give you 30,000 taels.
No,
50,000 taels.
That's the max.
Or,
along the way,
you can try to take your
revenge on me anytime.
You get a 50,000-tael share,
and you can still seek revenge on me.
But
revenge is one thing.
Don't get in the way of my fortune.
Fang.
How can you move?
I'm immune to all poisons.
I sat still just to hear
what you had to say.
Watch out for her blade.
It cuts through iron like clay.
Ghost Tycoon,
how are you handling things?
Don't move.
Kill the lad.
Hold on!
This is between my wife and me.
Stay out of it.
Fang, hold your breath!
The officers and bandits are in cahoots.
This makes me furious.
Let's see if you dare
to kill an imperial official.
So many men are bullying a weak woman.
What are you staring at?
Protect Officer Pu.
Go pull the officer back.
Move!
Officer.
Miss Zhang,
why bother?
A person as smart as you,
why attempt the impossible?
Catch him.
Slowly...
Gently.
Let's see how long
you can hold your breath.
The villains are right here.
Why aren't you from Liangzhou moving?
How will you report back to the Deputy?
If I don't die today,
those in Liangzhou,
from you to the Deputy,
will...
Officer!
Wake up, Officer.
Don't hurt her.
Fall.
Down you go.
What are you looking at?
Kill him.
Capture the Zhang lady.
(Preview of the Next Episode)
Are you also
an accomplice of the Zhang lady?
I wasn't before.
Now, I am.
Good people should live long.
Aren't good people
supposed to kill off all the evil ones?
Flying Eagle,
ask the Qin Demon
of Mount Pingfeng to help me.
I'll pretend last night never happened.
Keep going,
and listen to me.
Your son
has killed before?
=Remnants of Gold=